Guide to the Charles Seymour, President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and subject files, 1917-1954 1937-1950; 1937-1950; Series I
  - Pae - Pap, 1938-1949 (Box 123, Folder 1043)
  - Par - Pay, 1937-1950 (Box 123, Folder 1044)
  - Parents Magazine, 1937-1948 (Box 123, Folder 1045)
  - Paris, University of, 1948-1950 (Box 123, Folder 1046)
  - Parr, Albert E.
    See: box 125, folder 1060
  - Parsons, Francis and John, 1937-1939 (Box 123, Folder 1047)
  - Parsons Medal [in memory of William E. Parsons], 1941 (Box 123, Folder 1048)
  - Patent Policies Research Corporation Yale Corporation, Burkholder correspondence, 1943-1950 (Box 123, Folder 1049)
  - Patents, 1938-1946 (Box 124, Folder 1050)
  - Pe, 1937-1950 (Box 124, Folder 1051-1052)
  - Peabody Museum: Advisory Committee, 1938-1939 (Box 124, Folder 1053)
  - Peabody Museum: Bingham Oceanographic Foundation Department of Marine Research: Sears Gift: correspondence, 1937-1950 (Box 124, Folder 1054)
  - Peabody Museum Committee
    See: box 164, folder 1392
  - Peabody Museum: directors, trustees, meetings, etc., 1937-1950 (Box 124, Folder 1055-1056)
  - Peabody Museum: directors, trustees, meetings, etc., 1937-1950 (Box 125, Folder 1057)
  - Peabody Museum: directorship, etc., 1937-1938 (Box 125, Folder 1058)
  - Peabody Museum: Dr. Cornelius Osgood, undated (Box 125, Folder 1059)
  - Peabody Museum: Albert E. Parr, 1938-1946 (Box 125, Folder 1060)
  - Peace Proposal, 1940 (Box 125, Folder 1061)
  - Personal correspondence
    See: box 56, folder 492
  - Personnel Director, 1939-1950 (Box 125, Folder 1062-1063)
  - Personnel Director: AFL-CIO, Yale University Employees Local 142, 1941-1946 (Box 126, Folder 1064-1065)
  - Personnel Director: Labor Relations, Chiliastri and Pastro case, 1942 (Box 126, Folder 1066)
  - Personnel Director: R. Carter Nyman, 1939-1950 (Box 126, Folder 1067)
  - Personnel Director: report, 1939-1940 (Box 126, Folder 1068)
  - Personnel Director: strike, Yale University Service Employees [1941 Nov 10], 1941-1942 (Box 126, Folder 1069)
  - Personnel Policy Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1531
  - Personnel Problems Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1526
  - Personnel Study, Department of
    See: box 33, folder 287-288
  - Pet, 1937-1950 (Box 126, Folder 1070)
  - Pf - Pl, 1937-1950 (Box 126, Folder 1071-1072)
  - Pf - Pl, 1937-1950 (Box 127, Folder 1073)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1937-1944 (Box 127, Folder 1074)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1937-1950 (Box 127, Folder 1075)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Foundation, 1940-1950 (Box 127, Folder 1076)
  - Philosophy, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 127, Folder 1077)
  - Physical Fitness Institute, 1941 (Box 127, Folder 1078)
  - Physical Sciences and Mathematics, Division of, 1940-1950 (Box 127, Folder 1079)
  - Physics, Department of, 1937-1949 (Box 127, Folder 1080)
  - Pierson, Prof. George, 1942-1943 (Box 128, Folder 1081)
  - Pierson College
    See: box 158, folder 1341
  - Plant Science, Department of, 1938-1949 (Box 128, Folder 1082)
  - Po, 1937-1950 (Box 128, Folder 1083-1084)
  - Political Science, Department of [Department of Government and International Relations], 1937-1950 (Box 128, Folder 1085)
  - Political Union
    See: box 175, folder 1503
  - Pond, Raymond W.
    See: box 24, folder 198
  - Donald W. Porter Memorial Fund, 1939 (Box 128, Folder 1086)
  - Postwar Compulsory Military Training
    See: box 139, folder 1174-1175
  - Post-War Planning Board
    See: Series III box 52, folder 449 See: Series III box 168, folder 1440
  - Post-War Planning Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1527
  - Pr - Py, 1937-1950 (Box 128, Folder 1087)
  - Pr - Py, 1937-1950 (Box 129, Folder 1088)
  - President's Committee on Foreign Area and Language Studies, 1943-1948 (Box 129, Folder 1089)
  - President's Committee on Methods of Teaching Foreign Languages in the Undergraduate Schools, 1944-1945 (Box 129, Folder 1090)
  - President's Committee on Projects, 1947-1949 (Box 129, Folder 1091)
  - President's Committee on University Development, 1938-1941 (Box 129, Folder 1092)
  - President's Committee on University Development: Division of Engineering, 1939-1940 (Box 130, Folder 1093-1094)
  - President's Committee on University Development: Division of International Relations, 1941-1942 (Box 130, Folder 1095)
  - President's Committee on University Development: Division of Medicine and Public Health, 1938-1942 (Box 130, Folder 1096-1098)
  - President's Committee on University Development: Division of Research and Publication: A Professor's Theory and Its Practical Uses, 1939 (Box 130, Folder 1099)
  - President's Committee on University Entertainment, 1937-1950 (Box 130, Folder 1100)
  - President's Committee on University Policy as to Federal Support of Scientific Research, 1945, 1950 (Box 130, Folder 1100a)
  - President's Committee to Administer Language Teaching Program, 1944-1945 (Box 130, Folder 1101)
  - President's Committee to Confer with the University Officers on the Conditions of Labor of University Employees, 1937-1939 (Box 131, Folder 1102)
  - President's Committee to Study the Post-War Aspects of Campus Life - Spiritual and Moral, 1944-1946 (Box 131, Folder 1103)
  - President's Letters to Alumni
    See: box 166, folders 1428-1429
  - President's Reports, 1937-1943 (Box 131, Folder 1104-1109)
  - President's Reports, 1943-1950 (Box 132, Folder 1110-1113)
  - Princeton University, 1937-1950 (Box 132, Folder 1114-1116)
  - Prisoners of war
    See: box 169, folder 1451
  - Prizes, 1938-1950 (Box 132, Folder 1117)
  - Program for Educational Supervision
    See: box 159, folder 1344
  - Projects Committee
    See: box 129, folder 1091
  - Prudential Committee
    See: box 54, folder 477
  - Psycho Clinic -- Clinic of Child Development, 1938-1950 (Box 133, Folder 1118-1120)
  - Psychology, Department of, 1938-1950 (Box 133, Folder 1121)
  - Psychology, Department of: Committee to Consider Comprehensive Yale Program, 1945 (Box 133, Folder 1122)
  - Public Affairs, School of [J.G. Rogers-Dunham], 1937-1938 (Box 133, Folder 1123)
  - Publications, University, 1937-1950 (Box 133, Folder 1124)
  - Publicity, 1940-1950 (Box 133, Folder 1125)
  - Publicity: news releases, 1950 (Box 133, Folder 1126)
  - Publicity: Yale Conference on the Press and the War Crisis, 1942 February 6-7 (Box 134, Folder 1127)
  - Public Relations, 1936, 1942-1943 (Box 134, Folder 1128)
  - Public Relations: Committee on Alumni and Public Relations, 1936-1946 (Box 134, Folder 1129)
  - Public Relations: Tamblyn and Brown Inc., 1930-1941 (Box 134, Folder 1130)
  - Public Relations: Tamblyn and Brown Inc. Medical and Nursing School materials, 1938 (Box 134, Folder 1131)
  - Public Schools and British Opinion - a review, 1942 November 30 (Box 134, Folder 1132)
  - Publications Committee
    See: box 164, folder 1393
  - Q, 1937-1950 (Box 134, Folder 1133)
  - Ra, 1937-1950 (Box 134, Folder 1134)
  - Rabinowitz Foundation
  - Race Relations, Department of, 1939-1941 (Box 134, Folder 1135)
  - R.C.A. Scholarship Plan, 1945 (Box 134, Folder 1135a)
  - Rea - Rei, 1937-1950 (Box 134, Folder 1136-1137)
  - Reading period, 1938, 1940 (Box 135, Folder 1138)
  - Recommendations of Faculty members to other Universities, Colleges, Schools, etc., 1938-1950 (Box 135, Folder 1139)
  - Registration figures, 1937-1948 (Box 135, Folder 1140)
  - Ogden Reid Fellowship Foundation, 1948-1950 (Box 135, Folder 1141)
  - Rel - Rh, 1937-1950 (Box 135, Folder 1142)
  - Religion, Department of, 1946-1954 (Box 135, Folder 1143)
  - Religion, Student interest in
    See: box 149, folder 1254
  - Religious Life and Study Committee
    See: box 164, folder 1394
  - Report of the President of Yale University to the Alumni
    See: box 131, folder 1104-1109 See: box 132, folder 1110-1113
  - Retiring Allowances Committee
    See: box 54, folder 472
  - Retiring allowances for non-professional and non-executive employees, 1939-1948 (Box 135, Folder 1144)
  - Returning Servicemen: G.I. Bill of Rights, 1944 (Box 136, Folder 1145)
  - Returning Servicemen: minutes of the Executive Committee of the Yale Studies for Returning Servicemen, 1944-1945 (Box 136, Folder 1146)
  - Returning Servicemen: program of studies for, 1944-1949 (Box 136, Folder 1147-1148)
  - Rhodes Scholars, 1937-1949 (Box 136, Folder 1149)
  - Ri, 1937-1950 (Box 136, Folder 1150)
  - Rob - Rod, 1937-1950 (Box 136, Folder 1151)
  - Rob - Rod, 1937-1950 (Box 137, Folder 1152)
  - Robinson Foundation, 1937-1949 (Box 137, Folder 1153)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1937-1949 (Box 137, Folder 1154-1155)
  - Rockefeller Foundation: Paul Buck, 1948 (Box 137, Folder 1156)
  - Rog - Rop, 1937-1950 (Box 137, Folder 1157)
  - Rogers, James Gamble, 1937-1947 (Box 137, Folder 1158)
  - Rogers, James Grafton
    See: box 157, folder 1330
  - Room Contracts
    See: box 157, folder 1321
  - Roosevelt, Pres. and Mrs. Franklin D., 1941-1948 (Box 137, Folder 1159)
  - Ros - Rox, 1937-1950 (Box 137, Folder 1160)
  - Rostovtzeff, Prof. Michael I., Director of Archaeological Studies, 1930-1948 (Box 137, Folder 1161)
  - ROTC: Air Unit Proposal: Army Air Force, 1945-1950 (Box 138, Folder 1162)
  - ROTC: Army and Navy units: correspondence, 1938-1950 (Box 138, Folder 1163-1164)
  - ROTC: Army Medical unit, 1947-1949 (Box 138, Folder 1165)
  - ROTC: Citizens' Committee for Universal Military Training for Young Men, 1944-1948 (Box 138, Folder 1166)
  - ROTC: Military Science and Tactics, 1937-1950 (Box 138, Folder 1167-1169)
  - ROTC: Military Science and Tactics, 1937-1950 (Box 139, Folder 1170)
  - ROTC: Naval Agreement, 1941-1942 (Box 139, Folder 1171)
  - ROTC: Navy units, 1937-1945 (Box 139, Folder 1172-1173)
  - ROTC: Question of Postwar Compulsory Military Training, 1945-1948 (Box 139, Folder 1174-1175)
  - ROTC: Question of compulsory postwar military training, 1945-1948 (Box 140, Folder 1176)
  - ROTC: Postwar NROTC unit, undated (Box 140, Folder 1177-1180)
  - Rotival, Maurice, 1940-1950 (Box 140, Folder 1181)
  - Ru - Ry, 1937-1950 (Box 141, Folder 1182)
  - Ryerson, Edward L., 1938-1948 (Box 141, Folder 1183)
  - Sa, 1937-1950 (Box 141, Folder 1184-1185)
  - Saint Anthony's Hall and Trust, 1938-1946 (Box 141, Folder 1186)
  - Saint Elmo Society, 1938-1945 (Box 141, Folder 1187)
  - Salaries
    See: box 69, folder 594-596
  - Sanford, C. Hamilton Jr.
    See: box 7, folder 57
  - Sapir, Edward, 1937-1941 (Box 142, Folder 1188)
  - Saybrook College
    See: box 159, folder 1345
  - Saxon, O. Glenn, 1936-1944 (Box 142, Folder 1189)
  - Sc - Schl, 1937-1950 (Box 142, Folder 1190)
  - Schley, Reeve, 1937-1948 (Box 142, Folder 1191)
  - Schm - Schr, 1937-1950 (Box 142, Folder 1192)
  - Scholarship aid for sons of faculty members
    See: box 68, folder 585
  - Scholarship funds, reduction of
    See: box 147, folder 1238
  - Scholarships and Fellowships, 1939-1950 (Box 142, Folder 1193)
    See also: box 34, folder 295-297
  - Scholarships for children of alumni who died in the war, 1943-1944 (Box 142, Folder 1194)
  - Schu - Scu, 1937-1950 (Box 142, Folder 1195)
  - Science and Humanities: Yale's program [Division of Science], 1947 February 1 (Box 142, Folder 1196)
  - Science Departments: personnel expenditures [Yale-Harvard-Princeton], 1938-1939 (Box 142, Folder 1197)
  - Science Fund
    See: box 166, folder 1423
  - Sciences, Division of the, Committee
    See: box 163, folder 1384
  - Scientific Research Committeeants for Scientific Research
    See: box 130, folder 1100a See: box 176, folder 1515
  - Scientific Research Society of America, 1948-1949 (Box 143, Folder 1198)
  - Se - Sf, 1937-1950 (Box 143, Folder 1199)
  - Security Portfolio
  - Selective Service, 1948-1950 (Box 143, Folder 1200)
  - Service Bureaus, 1938-1950 (Box 143, Folder 1201)
  - Charles Seymour scholarship, 1950 (Box 143, Folder 1202)
  - Seymour, George Dudley, 1937-1942 (Box 143, Folder 1203)
  - Sha - Shel, 1937-1950 (Box 143, Folder 1204)
  - Sheffield Scientific School, 1937-1950 (Box 143, Folder 1205)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: Centennial, 1946-1947 (Box 143, Folder 1206)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: Centennial letters, 1946 (Box 143, Folder 1207)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: Deanship, possible candidates for, 1941 (Box 144, Folder 1208)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: minutes, 1937-1950 (Box 144, Folder 1209)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: organization, 1944-1945 (Box 144, Folder 1210)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: Trustees, 1936-1949 (Box 144, Folder 1211-1214)
  - Shem - Shy, 1937-1950 (Box 145, Folder 1215)
  - Sheppard, Provost John T., King"s College, 1937-1950 (Box 145, Folder 1216)
  - Sherrill, Bishop Henry Knox, 1938-1949 (Box 145, Folder 1217)
  - Sia - Sil, 1937-1950 (Box 145, Folder 1218)
  - Sigma Xi, 1937-1950 (Box 145, Folder 1219-1220)
  - Silliman College
    See: box 159, folder 1348
  - Silliman Lectureship, 1937-1950 (Box 145, Folder 1221)
  - Sim - Smy, 1937-1950 (Box 145, Folder 1222)
  - Slavic Languages and Literatures, 1947-1950 (Box 145, Folder 1223)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1938 (Box 145, Folder 1224)
  - Smith, 1937-1950 (Box 146, Folder 1225)
  - Smith, Elliott Dunlop
    See: box 159, folder 1346
  - Sn - So, 1937-1950 (Box 146, Folder 1226)
  - Social Science Planning Center, 1949-1950 (Box 146, Folder 1227)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1938-1947 (Box 146, Folder 1228)
  - Social Sciences Committee
    See: box 164, folder 1395
  - Social Sciences, Division of [also University Committee on the Social Sciences], 1947-1950 (Box 146, Folder 1229)
  - Society for the Promotion of Engineering Education
    See: box 64, folder 554
  - Sociology, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 146, Folder 1230)
  - Sophomore Counselors
    See: box 159, folder 1350
  - Southeast Asia Institute [formerly East Indies Institute of America, Inc.], 1943-1948 (Box 146, Folder 1231)
  - Southeast Asia Institute [formerly East Indies Institute of America, Inc.], 1943-1948 (Box 147, Folder 1232)
  - Sp, 1937-1950 (Box 147, Folder 1233)
  - Spanish and Italian, Department of, 1937-1950 (Box 147, Folder 1234)
  - Special Committee on Alumni Relations, 1938-1939 (Box 147, Folder 1235)
  - Special Committee on Biological Sciences, 1938-1939 (Box 147, Folder 1236)
  - Special Committee on Housing, 1945-1950 (Box 147, Folder 1237)
  - Special Committee on Scholarships: reduction of scholarship funds in the graduate and professional schools, 1941 (Box 147, Folder 1238)
  - Special Committee to Study Financial Aid Requirements in the Undergraduate Schools, 1946-1947 (Box 147, Folder 1239)
  - Special Committee to Study the Situation in the German Department and the Linguistics Group caused by the Death of Prof. Prokosch, 1938 (Box 147, Folder 1240)
  - Special Committee to Study the Status and Special Needs of Women Students at Yale, 1945-1946 (Box 147, Folder 1241)
  - Spiritual and moral aspects of campus life
    See: box 131, folder 1103
  - Sta, 1937-1950 (Box 147, Folder 1242)
  - Statistics, Committee on Program in, 1946-1950 (Box 148, Folder 1243)
  - Ste, 1937-1950 (Box 148, Folder 1244)
  - Sterling Bequest, 1937-1940 (Box 148, Folder 1245)
  - Sterling Fellowships, 1938-1950 (Box 148, Folder 1246)
  - Sterling Professorships, 1937-1950 (Box 148, Folder 1247)
  - Sti - Stu, 1937-1950 (Box 148, Folder 1248-1249)
  - Stoeckel, Robbins Battell, 1937-1946 (Box 148, Folder 1250)
  - Stoeckel Estate
    See: box 114, folder 975
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1938-1950 (Box 147, Folder 1251)
  - Strike - Yale University Service Employees
    See: box 126, folder 1069
  - Henry H. Strong Prize, 1937-1942 (Box 149, Folder 1252)
  - Student Charges
    See: box 34, folder 299
  - Student Christian Movement, 1938-1944 (Box 149, Folder 1253)
  - Student Employment, survey of
    See: box 34, folder 300
  - Student interest in religion, ways of stimulating, 1938 (Box 149, Folder 1254)
  - Student time, 1940 (Box 149, Folder 1255)
  - Su, 1937-1950 (Box 149, Folder 1256)
  - Summer session, 1941, 1945-1950 (Box 149, Folder 1257)
  - Sw - Sz, 1937-1950 (Box 149, Folder 1258)
  - Swiss military system, 1944-1945 (Box 149, Folder 1259)
  - Ta - Te, 1937-1950 (Box 149, Folder 1260-1261)
  - Ta - Te, 1937-1950 (Box 150, Folder 1262-1263)
  - Taft, Robert A., 1938-1950 (Box 150, Folder 1264)
  - Tamblyn and Brown Inc.
    See: box 134, folder 1130
  - Taxation (City and University Committees), 1933, 1937, 1939 (Box 150, Folder 1265)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1937-1949 (Box 150, Folder 1266)
  - Tenure
  - D.H.Terry Fund, 1937-1948 (Box 150, Folder 1267)
  - Th, 1937-1950 (Box 150, Folder 1268)
  - Th, 1937-1950 (Box 151, Folder 1269)
  - Three course plan, 1941-1942 (Box 151, Folder 1270)
  - Ti - To, 1937-1950 (Box 151, Folder 1271-1273)
  - Tighe, Laurence G: personal, 1941-1945 (Box 151, Folder 1274)
    See also: box 152, folder 1281
  - Timothy Dwight College
  - Tr, 1937-1950 (Box 151, Folder 1275-1276)
  - Transportation Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1528
  - Treasurer"s Office, 1937-1950 (Box 152, Folder 1277-1280)
  - Treasurer"s Office: Associate Treasurer in Charge of Investments: Laurence G. Tighe, 1937-1938 (Box 152, Folder 1281)
  - Treasurer"s Office: Committee to Study the Problem of Overhead in Connection with Outside Grants, 1937-1938 (Box 152, Folder 1282)
  - Treasurer"s Office: University security portfolio, 1944, 1948-1949 (Box 152, Folder 1283)
  - Trippe, Juan T., 1949-1950 (Box 152, Folder 1284)
  - Trumbull College
    See: box 159, folder 1351
  - Trustees
    See: box 55, folder 485
  - Tu - Ty, 1937-1950 (Box 152, Folder 1285)
  - Tu - Ty, 1937-1950 (Box 153, Folder 1286)
  - Tuition, 1934-1947 (Box 153, Folder 1287-1288)
  - Turner, Ralph
    See: box 82, folder 715
  - Tuttle, Emerson
    See: box 157, folder 1323
  - Tyng Trophy
    See: box 158, folder 1338
  - U, 1937-1950 (Box 153, Folder 1289-1291)
  - U, 1937-1950 (Box 154, Folder 1292-1294)
  - Undergraduate activities: airplane accident, Seattle, 1949 January 2 (Box 154, Folder 1295)
  - Undergraduate activities: general, 1937-1949 (Box 154, Folder 1296)
  - Undergraduate activities: Loomis Havemeyer, 1948 (Box 154, Folder 1297)
  - Undergraduate activities: Inter Fraternity Council, 1937-1941 (Box 155, Folder 1298)
  - Undergraduate activities: literary, 1937-1950 (Box 155, Folder 1299)
  - Undergraduate activities: musical [Director - Marshall Bartholomew], 1938-1948 (Box 155, Folder 1300)
  - Undergraduate activities: post-war
    See: box 156, folder 1319
  - Undergraduate activities: rules and regulations, 1922, 1937-1941 (Box 155, Folder 1301)
  - Undergraduate Activities Committee
    See: box 177, folder 1529-1530
  - Undergraduate Colleges, 1937-1949 (Box 155, Folder 1302)
  - Undergraduate Colleges:
    - Berkeley College, 1937-1950 (Box 155, Folder 1303-1304)
    - Berkeley College - King"s College; Amicable Concord, 1938-1944 (Box 155, Folder 1305)
    - Berkeley College - King"s College: Guggenheimer Invitation, 1940-1941 (Box 155, Folder 1306)
    - Berkeley College: Master Samuel B. Hemingway, 1938-1950 (Box 155, Folder 1307)
    - Branford College, 1937-1949 (Box 156, Folder 1308)
    - Calhoun College, 1937-1950 (Box 156, Folder 1309)
    - Calhoun College: Master Arnold Whitridge, 1941-1945 (Box 156, Folder 1310)
    - Undergraduate Colleges Council of Masters, 1937-1950 (Box 156, Folder 1311-1312)
      See also: series IV, box 200, folder 1-6 series IV, box 201, folder 7-10
      - Council of Masters, Committee on Allocation of Students to the Colleges, 1937-1949 (Box 156, Folder 1313)
      - committee on Allocations Technique, 1940 (Box 156, Folder 1314)
      - Special Committee to Study the System of Allocations, 1942 May (Box 156, Folder 1315)
      - Committee on Bursary Appointments, 1938-1946 (Box 156, Folder 1316)
      - Committee on College Funds, 1941-1943 (Box 156, Folder 1317)
      - Committee on Personnel [Fellows], 1944-1948 (Box 156, Folder 1318)
      - Committee on Post War Undergraduate Activities, 1944-1945 (Box 156, Folder 1319)
      - Committee on Relations between Fraternities and the Colleges, 1938-1944 (Box 156, Folder 1320)
      - Room contracts, 1943 (Box 157, Folder 1321)
    - Davenport College, 1937-1950 (Box 157, Folder 1322)
      - Master Emerson Tuttle, 1937-1946 (Box 157, Folder 1323)
      - Mastership, 1946 (Box 157, Folder 1324)
      - Record of the Fellows v.2, 1948 (Box 157, Folder 1325)
    - Dining halls, 1937-1942 (Box 157, Folder 1326)
    - Directories, 1939-1942 (Box 157, Folder 1327)
    - Timothy Dwight College, 1938-1950 (Box 157, Folder 1328)
      - Master Frederick A. Godley, 1942-1948 (Box 157, Folder 1329)
      - Master James Grafton Rogers, 1938-1942 (Box 157, Folder 1330)
      - Mastership, successor to Mr. Godley, 1947 (Box 157, Folder 1331)
      - Mastership, successor to Mr. Rogers, 1942 (Box 157, Folder 1332)
    - Fellows, 1937-1950 (Box 158)
    - Mr. and Mrs. E.S. Harkness, 1937-1950 (Box 158, Folder 1334-1335)
    - Inter-College Athletics, 1937-1950 (Box 158, Folder 1336-1337)
      - Tyng Trophy, 1938-1950 (Box 158, Folder 1338)
    - Libraries, 1938-1944 (Box 158, Folder 1339)
    - Masters, 1946-1950 (Box 158, Folder 1340)
    - Pierson College, 1937-1950 (Box 158, Folder 1341)
      - Master Prof. Arnold Wolfers, 1940-1947 (Box 159, Folder 1342)
      - Mastership, 1949-1950 (Box 159, Folder 1343)
    - Program [Fund] for Educational Supervision, 1937-1941 (Box 159, Folder 1344)
    - Saybrook College, 1937-1950 (Box 159, Folder 1345)
      - Master Elliott Dunlap Smith, 1938-1946 (Box 159, Folder 1346)
      - Mastership, 1945-1946 (Box 159, Folder 1347)
    - Siliman College, 1938-1950 (Box 159, Folder 1348)
      - Mastership, 1938-1940, 1947 (Box 159, Folder 1349)
    - Sophomore counselors, 1940-1944 (Box 159, Folder 1350)
    - Trumbull College, 1937-1949 (Box 159, Folder 1351)
      - Master Charles H. Warren, 1938-1940 (Box 160, Folder 1352)
      - Mastership, 1937-1938, 1945 (Box 160, Folder 1353-1354)
  - Undergraduate Enrollment, 1929-1938 (Box 160, Folder 1355)
    See also: box 56, folder 489
  - Undergraduate Scholarship Committee of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences
    See: box 34, folder 301
  - Union Theological Seminary, 1945-1946 (Box 160, Folder 1356)
  - United Nations Organization (UNO), 1945-1949 (Box 160, Folder 1357-1358)
  - United Service Organizations (USO), 1941-1942 (Box 160, Folder 1359)
  - United States, 1937-1950 (Box 160, Folder 1360-1361)
  - United States, 1937-1950 (Box 161, Folder 1362-1365)
  - United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y., 1937-1950 (Box 161, Folder 1366)
  - United States Naval Academy: Board of Visitors, 1932-1949 (Box 162, Folder 1367-1368)
  - United States Treasury Department: U.S. Defense Savings Bonds, etc., 1942-1946 (Box 162, Folder 1369)
  - University Club of Boston, 1938-1950 (Box 162, Folder 1370)
  - University Club of New York, 1937-1950 (Box 162, Folder 1371-1372)
  - University Club of New York, 1937-1950 (Box 163, Folder 1373)
  - University Club of Washington, 1940, 1946 (Box 163, Folder 1374)
  - University Committees
    See: box 175, folder 1509
  - University Council, 1937-1950 (Box 163, Folder 1375)
    note: University Council and University Development appear to be closely related.
    - Alumni organization, 1947 (Box 163, Folder 1376)
    - Biographical data on new members, undated (Box 163, Folder 1377)
    - Chart of organization, undated (Box 163, Folder 1378)
    - Committee on the Art Gallery, 1948-1949 (Box 163, Folder 1379)
    - Committee on the Division of the Arts: Architecture, Painting, and Sculpture, 1948-1950 (Box 163, Folder 1380)
    - Committee on the Division of the Arts: Drama, 1948 (Box 163, Folder 1381)
    - Committee on the Division of the Humanities, 1948-1949 (Box 163, Folder 1382)